Saul Newbury – Front-End Web-Developer

Personal Statement

In September of 2021 I decided on becoming a front end developer, having incurring tinnitus which prevented me from continuing as a guitar instructor and performer. Up to then I'd undertaken several web projects that included a simple static website to promote my music, and the maintenance of a website for Distant Voice (telecommunications services), built on the Wordpress platform.

When I decided on web development for my career, I began learning Javascript from online on-demand courses in tandem with one-to-one, weekly tutorials with an industry professional. My tutor helped outline a pathway from student to junior developer and so I began learning React, whilst also familiarising myself with Express and MongoDB in order to have preliminary insight across the stack. Now eight months from when I began last September, I have built a website showcasing several portfolio pieces demonstrating my experience to date.

I am very excited to hone what I've learned so far, and further expand my knowledge within a professional setting. I will bring tenacity and enthusiasm to your team, with an eye for detail and appetite for learning.

I'd love the opportunity to chat, please get in touch to explore whether I'd be a good fit for your team or project.

Technical Skills

Css

Html

Sass

JavaScript

React

RESTful APIs

SVG

GSAP

NPM

Github

Transferable Skills

As private guitar tutor and musician:

Marketing and promotion
Planning and time management
Clear and affective communication
Attention to detail
Strong resource investigator

Employment History

0040	
2019 – now	Graphic design and web-development
2017 - 110W	Diabilic design and web-development

Distant Voice

Sep – Oct 2018 Graphic design and web-development

Copyology

June – Aug (2018) Sole designer/creator of S4M's Fusio Sales Deck

S4M

2011 – 2018 Self-promotion, branding and website design

Private guitar tutor and musician

Sept – Dec (2013) Designer Programmer and Editor

Elemental Practice LLP

Telefonica's Campus Party 2013, O2 arena

Aug 2010 – Oct 2013 Content writer and designer for slideshow

presentations

Applaud Entertainment

Education

2007 – 2009 BA Creative Sound Design for New Media

Academy of Contemporary Music

2006 – 2007 Music Production Higher Diploma

Academy of Contemporary Music

Also busy with

Playing guitar and crafting songs A novel or two Adventuring, in nature

And I like doing short tutorials, creative coding, learning new tricks, and generally expanding and sharpening my dev toolset.